Tyler Adkins

adkinsty@icloud.com 517 927 3467 723 S. Main St. Ann Arbor MI 48104 adkinsty.github.io

Summary

Computational cognitive neuroscientist with 6 years of experience designing experiments and analyzing data.

Skills

Bayesian statistics, experimental design, mathematical modeling, data visualization, machine learning, simulation, image processing, formal reasoning, scientific writing, public speaking, literature review, teaching

Tools

R, Python, Stan, JavaScript, Git, Bash, AWS, LaTeX, Illustrator, SQL, MATLAB, C++, HTML

Employment

9/2017 – Present *University of Michigan* Graduate Research Fellow Ann Arbor, MI Designed psychophysical experiments, preprocessed large high-dimensional datasets, built parametric and nonparametric statistical models, collaborated with teams of scientists on interdisciplinary research projects, reported research findings in reputable journals and conferences, mentored colleagues on data analysis.

1/2018 – 4/2020 *University of Michigan* Graduate Student Instructor Ann Arbor, MI Created educational materials and assessments for instructors and students in large lecture courses, provided instruction and tutoring to students in multiple discussion sections, graded written assignments and quizzes

9/2015 – 9/2017 *University of Michigan* Research Assistant Ann Arbor, MI Configured hardware and software for eye-tracking systems, implemented econometric models of decision-making.

Education

9/2017 – Present	University of Michigan	Ph.D. in Psychology	Ann Arbor, MI
1/2015 – 9/2017	University of Michigan	B.A. in Cognitive Science	Ann Arbor, MI

Awards

2021	Swets Award for Psych. Science (\$25k)
2020	NSF RAPID grant (\$200k)
2019	NSF GRFP (honorable mention)
2018	Scholarship in Math. Psych. (\$3k)
2017	Rackham Merit Fellowship (\$100k)
2016	Phi Kappa Phi
2015	Sweeney Merit Scholarship (\$3k)

Service

	5	
2021	Departmental Associate	
2020	Forum Committee	
2020	Admissions Committee	
2019	Social Committee	
2018	Recruitment Committee	

Publications

^{*}Shared first authorship